Guide to the Stone Circles Records, 1995-2012 RL.11003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Stone Circles records
1995-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Stone Circles
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
RL.11003
11.4 Linear Feet 19 boxes
The Stone Circles records contain materials documenting the history of the organization. These include press clippings, board meeting minutes. staff and financial information, program files, newsletters, event information, and correspondence.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Collection Overview
Established in 1995, Stone Circles is a leading organization in the national movement toward a more spiritually-based form of activism. SC has introduced thousands of social change leaders and organizations to spiritual and reflective practice through workshops, retreats, trainings and strategic convenings. Stone Circles at the Stone House is located in Mebane, NC on 70 acres of farmland.
Related Material
Claudia Horwitz papers, 1988-2012 (Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library)
Arrangement
Original folder titles and arrangement have been preserved.
Activists -- North Carolina; Spirituality; Social justice -- North Carolina; Nonprofit organizations -- North Carolina; Activism -- Religous aspects; Stone Circles; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Accession (2013-0186)
  - Miscellaneous - Undated (Box 1)
  - Fundraising: Stone House - Undated (Box 1)
  - The Stone House: Early Days - Undated (Box 1)
  - Survey (basis for choosing people to profit), Part 1 - 2006 (Box 2)
  - Survey (basis for choosing people to profit), Part 2 - 2006 (Box 2)
  - Survey (basis for choosing people to profit), Part 3 - 2006 (Box 2)
  - ORG Materials: Miscellaneous - Undated (Box 2)
  - Stations of Reflection: Signs - Undated (Box 2)
  - Communication/Handouts - Undated (Box 2)
  - Web-Site Copy and Design - Undated (Box 2)
  - NAV: Next Steps - Undated (Box 2)
  - Navigator's First Report - Undated (Box 3)
  - Basics/Communication - Undated (Box 3)
  - Navigation - Undated (Box 3)
  - Conversation Notes - Undated (Box 3)
  - SF Conversation - Undated (Box 3)
  - Notebook: Originals - Undated (Box 3)
  - Navigator Report #1 - Undated (Box 3)
  - Workshops (One-on-One) - Undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous - 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Politics of Meaning - Undated (Box 3)
  - City Year - 1997 (Box 3)
  - Do Something - 1997 (Box 3)
  - C.O.O.L. - 1991-1997 (Box 3)
  - Call to Renewal - 1997 (Box 3)
  - Southern Oral History Program - Undated (Box 3)
  - Alt. Consulting - 1998 (Box 3)
  - Kirk Ridge - 1998-2005 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous - 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - Second Journey - 2000-2004 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous - 2001 (Box 4)
  - C.O.O.L. Conference - January 2001 (Box 4)
  - Asheville - January 2001 (Box 4)
  - NGL Workshop - January 2001 (Box 4)
  - Care for the Caregiver - February 2001 (Box 4)
  - CFG Planning - March 2001 (Box 4)
  - Pfeiffer Collage - 2001 (Box 4)
  - ASHOKA - 2001 (Box 4)
  - Contemplative Mind: Net Project - 2001 (Box 4)
  - Duke Non-Profit Management Installation - 2001 (Box 4)
  - Homeless Conference Workshop - November 2001 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous - 2002 (Box 4)
  - Leadership Learning Community - 2002 (Box 4)
  - Public Allies Reunion - June 2002 (Box 4)
  - DWW: Writing as Practice - June 2002 (Box 4)
  - NGL: Module 4 - June 2002 (Box 4)
  - SKS Inward Bound - October 2002 (Box 5)
  - Wildacres - October 2002 (Box 5)
  - Making Money, Making Change - September 2002 (Box 5)
  - Duke Inst. Power - September 2002 (Box 5)
  - AIDS Services Alliance - October 2002 (Box 5)
  - Peace Leap - 2002 (Box 5)
  - Echoing Green - November 2002 (Box 5)
  - Daily Practice, Trinity Center - November 2002 (Box 5)
  - Spirited Change in Santa Cruz - December 3-5, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Movement Strategy Center - December 2002 (Box 5)
  - SPAN - December 2002 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous - 2003 (Box 5)
  - Class Matters Workshop - March 2003 (Box 5)
  - Creating Space - May 2003 (Box 5)
  - Institute Conflict - September 2003 (Box 5)
  - Vallecitos - 2003 (Box 5)
  - CIN Conference - October 2003 (Box 5)
  - NC Public Allies - Undated (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous - 2004 (Box 5)
  - Coordinating Progressive Durham - 2004 (Box 5)
  - Guilford College - January 2004 (Box 6)
  - Building Movement - 2004 (Box 6)
  - Standing Together - April 2004 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous - 2005 (Box 6)
  - NGL: Sustainable Activism - April 5-7, 2005 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous - 2006 (Box 6)
  - Duke: Class - September 2006 (Box 6)
  - Sacred Slam - 2006 (Box 6)
  - Guilford - 2006 (Box 6)
  - Highlander - August 2007 (Box 6)
  - Teambuilding: Open Source, December 2007 (Box 6)
  - Workshops - 2008-2009 (Box 6)
  - Events, etc. - 2009-2010 (Box 6)
  - Warren Wilson - 2011 (Box 6)
  - N.C. ICE Watch - 2011 (Box 6)
  - HIP - 2011 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous - 2012 (Box 6)
  - Events - 2007 (Box 6)
  - Fellowship Communication - Undated (Box 6)
  - Fellowship Gathering - March 2004 (Box 7)
  - Ripples Applications - 2004 (Box 7)
  - Ripples Training - November 2004 (Box 7)
  - Ripples: Evals, Agenda, Contacts - 2004 (Box 7)
  - Next Ripples Training: Angel's Nest - March 2005 (Box 7)
  - Ripples Agenda - March 2005 (Box 7)
  - Fellows Gathering - August 2004 (Box 7)
  - Fellowship Reunion - 2005 (Box 7)
  - Harvard Divinity School - Undated (Box 7)
  - Garrison Writings - Undated (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous - Undated (Box 7)
  - Garrison Transcripts - Undated (Box 8)
  - Garrison Logistics - Undated (Box 8)
  - Garrison Report - 2005 (Box 8)
  - Ideology/Strategy Gathering, Part 1 of 2 - Undated (Box 8)
  - Ideology/Strategy Gathering, Part 2 of 2 - Undated (Box 8)
  - Being Change - August 2005 (Box 8)
  - Being Change - 2005 (Box 8)
  - Vallecitos Retreat: Apps/Evals - August 2005 (Box 8)
  - Seeding Sustainable Activism - 2006-2007 (Box 9)
  - Katrina Neighbors - 2006 (Box 9)
  - GI Rept. Mailing - 2006 (Box 9)
  - Being Change: Angel's Rest (Western MA) - 2006 (Box 9)
  - Being Change Retreat - 2006 (Box 9)
  - Being Change: Durham - February 2007 (Box 9)
  - US Social Forum - June 2007 (Box 9)
  - Being Change: Vallecitos - 2007 (Box 9)
  - Open House - 2007 (Box 9)
  - Being Change - April 2008 (Box 9)
  - What Has To Be Done - October 2003 (Box 9)
  - Being Change - November 2008 (Box 10)
  - Suso: Overview Documents - 2008-2009 (Box 10)
  - Suso Cohort Application - Undated (Box 10)
  - Suso Participants - Undated (Box 10)
  - Suso Gatherings - 2008-2009 (Box 10)
  - Yoga of Social Change - April 2009 (Box 10)
  - Tree of Intentions and Wishes - September 2009 (Box 10)
  - Freedom Through Understanding - 2009 (Box 10)
  - MLK: Day of Practice - January 2009 (Box 10)
  - Ripples - 2010 (Box 10)
  - USSF: Detriot - 2010 (Box 10)
  - Ground Up - 2010 (Box 11)
  - Vipasanna - 2010 (Box 11)
  - Yoga of Social Change - October 2010 (Box 11)
  - YSC (NC and DC) - April 2011 (Box 11)
  - Institute - 2011 (Box 11)
  - Transforming Movements: Inst. Report - 2011 (Box 11)
  - Deeper Practices - 2012 (Box 11)
  - Food Justice - 2012 (Box 11)
  - Food Justice: Evaluations - January 2012 (Box 11)
  - Yoga of Social Change - 2013 (Box 11)
  - Diana Autin - Undated (Box 11)
  - Kenny Bailey, Fellow - Undated (Box 11)
  - Daniel Barber - Undated (Box 11)
  - John Bielenson - Undated (Box 11)
  - Miriam Biber - Undated (Box 12)
  - Billie Burney - Undated (Box 12)
  - Liz Cedillo - Undated (Box 12)
  - Arrington Chambliss, Fellow - Undated (Box 12)
  - Ed Chaney - Undated (Box 12)
  - Lisa Charley, Fellow - Undated (Box 12)
  - Tony Deefell - Undated (Box 12)
  - Michael Edwards - Undated (Box 12)
  - Georgann Eubanks - Undated (Box 12)
  - Chantelle Fisher-Borne - Undated (Box 12)
  - Jonah Friedman: Wonder Works - Undated (Box 12)
  - Katherine Fulton - Undated (Box 12)
  - Albino Garcia, Fellow - Undated (Box 12)
  - Simon Greer, Fellow - Undated (Box 12)
  - Gita Golati-Partee - Undated (Box 12)
  - Raquel Gutierrez - Undated (Box 12)
  - Russell Herman - Undated (Box 12)
  - Gazette - March 2005-April 2005 (Box 12)
  - Jay Iversion - Undated (Box 12)
  - Val Joseph - Undated (Box 12)
  - Jim and Cheryl Keen - Undated (Box 13)
  - Social Policy - 1993 (Box 1)
  - Chapel Hill News - 1996 (Box 1)
  - Triangle Community Foundation - 1999 (Box 1)
  - Herald Sun - 1999 (Box 1)
  - Independent Weekly - 2000 (Box 1)
  - Sojourner's Article - March 2000-April 2000 (Box 1)
  - Independent Weekly - 2000 (Box 1)
  - News and Observer - February 2000 (Box 1)
  - News and Observer - December 2000 (Box 1)
  - Herald Sun - 2002 (Box 1)
  - Winston-Salem Journal - 2002 (Box 1)
  - Jewish Exponent - 2002 (Box 1)
  - News and Observer - 2003 (Box 1)
  - Utne - 2006 (Box 1)
  - Yes! Magazine - 2006 (Box 1)
  - Chronicle of Philanthropy - 2007 (Box 1)
  - Turning Wheel - 2008 (Box 1)
  - The Times News - 2008 (Box 1)
  - News and Record - 2009 (Box 1)
  - Mebane Enterprise - 2010 (Box 1)
  - Local Advisory Board Meeting - Undated (Box 1)
  - Financial Resources - Undated (Box 1)
  - Staff - Undated (Box 1)
  - Big Picture Strategy - Undated (Box 1)
  - Land and Buildings - Undated (Box 1)
  - Board - Undated (Box 1)
  - Capture the Story - Undated (Box 1)
  - Jennifer Keenan - Undated (Box 13)
  - Annie Lanzillotto - Undated (Box 13)
  - Blaine Lukkar and Judy Harvey - Undated (Box 13)
  - Joanna Macy - Undated (Box 13)
  - IOEN: Reports and Summaries - Undated (Box 13)
  - Original Documents: Random Assortment - Undated (Box 1)
  - Charles McKinney - Undated (Box 13)
  - Virgil Moore - Undated (Box 13)
  - Ched Myers - Undated (Box 13)
  - Ellen O'Grady - Undated (Box 13)
  - Scott Pryor, Fellow - Undated (Box 13)
  - Juan Reed - Undated (Box 13)
  - Michael Regan - Undated (Box 13)
  - Stanely Richards - Undated (Box 13)
  - Sharon Ryan - Undated (Box 13)
  - Maribeth Saleem-Tanner - Undated (Box 13)
  - Terry Sanford - Undated (Box 13)
  - Saul Sarabia - Undated (Box 14)
  - David Sawyer - Undated (Box 14)
  - Jason Scott - Undated (Box 14)
  - Mab Segrest - Undated (Box 14)
  - Lisa Sullivan - Undated (Box 14)
  - Peter Tavernise - Undated (Box 14)
  - Alice Tejada - Undated (Box 14)
  - Rachel Timoner: Organizing Projects - Undated (Box 14)
  - Ingrid - Undated (Box 14)
  - Omar Wasow - Undated (Box 14)
  - Emilee Whitehurst - Undated (Box 14)
  - Angel Kyodo Williams, Fellow - Undated (Box 14)
  - Mel Williams - Undated (Box 14)
  - Billy Wimsatt - Undated (Box 14)
  - Odin Zackman - Undated (Box 14)
  - Maura Wolf - Undated (Box 14)
  - Everyday Leadership: Leader's Guide - Undated (Box 15)
  - Mindwing - Undated (Box 15)
  - Evaluations: First Circle - 1995 (Box 15)
  - First Interfaith Celebration - December 1995 (Box 15)
  - Second Circle: Mailings and Meetings - Undated (Box 15)
  - Statements of Commitment - 1995 (Box 15)
  - First Circle: Info Sessions - 1995 (Box 15)
  - Summer Training Info - 1996 (Box 15)
  - Second Circle Statements - Undated (Box 15)
  - Third Circle - Undated (Box 15)
  - Interfaith Celebration - 1997 (Box 16)
  - Interfaith Celebration - 1998 (Box 16)
  - Interfaith Celebration - 1999 (Box 16)
  - A Stone's Throw: Release - November 1999 (Box 16)
  - Spirit in Action - 2000 (Box 16)
  - Ripples: Responses - 2000 (Box 16)
  - Ripples: Returned Forms - 2000 (Box 16)
  - Ripples: Mailings - 2000 (Box 16)
  - Ripples: Report - 2000 (Box 16)
  - Ripples: Plans and Materials - Undated (Box 16)
  - Ripples: Pre-Training Evaluations - 2000 (Box 17)
  - Ripples: Evaluations and Reflections - 2000 (Box 17)
  - Ripples: Notebook - 2000 (Box 17)
  - Ripples: Agenda - 2000 (Box 17)
  - Worksheets - Undated (Box 17)
  - Follow-Up Packet - Undated (Box 17)
  - Ripples: Evenings/Events - Undated (Box 17)
  - Ripples: Planning - 2001 (Box 17)
  - Ripples: Applications - 2001 (Box 17)
  - Ripples: Agenda - 2001 (Box 18)
  - Ripples: Notes - 2001 (Box 18)
  - Ripples: Tasting Freedom Evening - 2001 (Box 18)
  - Ripples: Participant Evals - 2001 (Box 18)
  - Ripples: Evals - 2001 (Box 18)
  - Ripples: Follow Up/Report - December 2002 (Box 18)
  - Interfaith Celebration - December 2002 (Box 18)
  - Iraq: Anti-War Stuff - 2002-2003 (Box 18)
  - Peace AD - 2003 (Box 18)
  - Reflection Hours - 2003 (Box 18)
  - Vigil - January 18, 2003 (Box 19)
  - May Gathering: Logistics - 2003 (Box 19)
  - Trainer Gathering: Agenda - May 2003 (Box 19)
  - May Packet - Undated (Box 19)
  - November Gathering: Fellowship - 2003 (Box 19)
  - Love and Thank-You Notes (Part 1 of 3) - Undated (Box 19)
  - Love and Thank-You Notes (Part 2 of 3) - Undated (Box 19)
  - Love and Thank-You Notes (Part 3 of 3) - Undated (Box 19)